# **David Sanderson**

## Software Engineer



sanderdj90@gmail.com



505-604-5355



github.com/d-sanderson



linkedin.com/in/d-sanderson

## **Professional Summary**

Albuquerque-based Fullstack Developer with a strong passion for designing, building, and deploying custom websites/software applications. Most familiar with React but also proficient with Node, Express, C#, CSS, HTML, PHP(Laravel) and willing to learn new technologies. Resilient and curious problem solver with 3 years of development experience, excellent interpersonal skills, and the tenacity to solve difficult problems.

## Experience

#### Software Engineer, Digital Ops @ Meow Wolf

April 2021 - present // Albuquerque, NM

#### Jr. Software Engineer @ iTeam Consulting

February 2020 - April 2021 // Albuquerque, NM

Technologies used: Gatsby, Git, React, C#, SharePoint, Jest, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Netlify, Active Directory, Exchange, O365, Azure, various ORMs

- Migrate multiple legacy websites to the JAM stack using GatsbyJS
- Maintain and regularly update legacy ASP.NET Web applications (MVC 5.0 and Razor Pages).
- Implement designs using Figma
- Created a Gatsby application that sources data from Sharepoint Lists to programmatically create web pages.

#### Resident Web Developer @ Activate New Mexico

October 2019 - February 2020 // Albuquerque, NM

Technologies used: React, Gatsby, GQL, WordPress, MySQL, MySQL Workbench

- Provided technical support and consultation to early-stage startups.
- Draft and execute project charters.
- Created 3 websites for participating startups
- Conducted database design for a health-care startup.

#### Freelance Web Developer

December 2018 - October 2019 // Albuquerque, NM

<u>Technologies used:</u> React, Gatsby, Wordpress (Genesis Framework)

- Helped local business owners throughout New Mexico revamp their online presence and
- Designed, built, and deployed custom websites for various clients, assisted with maintenance, updates, and hosting.

### Skills

#### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6), C#, HTML, CSS/SCSS,

#### Libraries and Frameworks

React, Gatsby, Next, D3, .NET, Node.js, Tailwind, Emotion, and Material UI

#### **Tools and Platforms**

Git, Netlify, Netlify CMS, Docker, Hasura, Airtable, GraphQL

#### Design

Figma, Responsive Design, Inkscape

#### Education

#### University of New Mexico

2008 - 2013 // Albuquerque, NM Bachelors of Science - Evolutionary Anthropology

#### Amy Biehl High School

2004 - 2008 // Albuquerque, NM High School Diploma Studied website design

#### Certifications

- C# Fundamentals
- Testing .NET Code with xUnit
- CNM Ingenuity Cert. of Completion -Fullstack Bootcamp October 2018

## **Current Projects**

- Designing and building data visualization for Vital Spaces Intersections Event (Santa Fe, Summer 2021) . Using Figma, D3, and React.
- Building the new credits site for Meow Wolf using NextJS and Airtable